(An Awesome Day)
- Nice to see you. - Nice to see you.
All right.
The guest for today's Rainbow Live is...
a distinguished individual on a global scale.
- Didn't he win an award? - He did.
- He won the Gold Glove Award. - He's...
- Yes. - the first Korean to win it.
- The 1st Asian player to win it. - The 1st Asian player to win it.
- The Gold Glove Award for Utility. - Yes.
It means he's the best defensive player...
- in the US. - Right.
Is that equivalent to winning the Ballon d'Or?
- Yes. - That's it.
And he rarely stars on variety shows, right?
- He rarely does. - Right.
Did you believe it when you heard he'd be on the show?
He's my favorite baseball player.
I bet baseball fans have been waiting for this day.
All right. He's the first Korean MLB player...
to win the Gold Glove Award.
He's a world-class shortstop.
It's Awesome Kim, Kim Ha Seong.
For real?
(Kim Ha Seong shows up.)
This feels surreal.
(In 2019, he scored the most runs in the KBO league.)
(He won the Golden Glove Award 3 years in a row since 2018.)
(He also excelled as the national team's starting shortstop.)
(2017: Silver medal from the Asia Professional Baseball Championship)
(2018: Golden Glove Award from the KBO, gold medal)
(2019: The most runs in the KBO, the Best Batter of the Year,)
(Golden Glove Award from the KBO, runner-up in the WBSC Premier12)
(Afterward, he joined the MLB.)
(He proved his talent by making a strong impression.)
(He proudly earned his place among the league's top players.)
(The first Korean player...)
(to win the Gold Glove Award in the MLB.)
(Baseball Player Kim Ha Seong)
(We welcome you from the bottom of our heart.)
- This feels surreal. - My gosh. Hello.
Hello.
(Catch my ball.)
- Hey. - Come to the center. Hello.
- Please come to the center. - It's like I'm dreaming.
This feels surreal.
All right. Say hello to our viewers first.
Okay.
Hello. I'm a baseball player. My name is Kim Ha Seong.
Why...
- Are you that nervous? - No.
(Nervously shifting his gaze)
He's an extrovert.
But from what I know, he's just shy in the beginning.
- Oh, he is? - Yes.
(Thank you.)
It's your first time meeting all of us, right?
Yes. I've only seen you on TV.
How does it feel to be in the presence of superstars?
(Trailing off)
It feels surreal. It's like I'm watching TV.
(How cute.)
I'd like to ask you how it feels to be here...
for the first time.
Well, I think it's a bit small.
- Compared to what you saw on TV? - Yes. The studio...
- It's smaller than the MLB. - No.
Our studio is too small to host a superstar.
Gosh, no.
By the way, I really wanted to meet you.
- Can I shake your hand? - Sure.
You have such big hands.
- Look at that. - Your hands are so big.
- Can I compare our hands? - Your hand...
(Everyone wants to compare their hands.)
His fingers are a joint longer than mine.
- He has big hands. - His hands are so big.
My left hand...
(Shy)
- I hear you're a free agent now. - Yes.
They're discussing 70 million dollars...
for your annual salary.
So you can join any team now, right?
I just know that my agent is working hard.
Is there a team you want to join?
- San Francisco? - No comment.
- Isn't that a sensitive question? - Is it?
Well, he doesn't have to answer it.
I'm going to ask him how much money he has.
- Okay. - Do you think you can answer that?
- Yes. - Okay.
All right. Now that you're in the Rainbow family,
once you make your decision,
you must tell us first. Okay?
- Sure. - Okay.
- Really? - You'll tell us first?
(Chuckling)
- Could you sign my uniform later? - Sure.
- He'll take pictures too. - Please sign it.
I must post it on my social media.
(He'll go on Moomoo's social media which only features superstars.)
All right. Let's check out the day-to-day life of Kim Ha Seong,
the MLB player.
(Let's check it out.)
(A Major Day)
- "A Major Day." - "A Major Day."
(Squirming)
Your house is really dark.
Gosh, the angle of your hand...
- He's throwing a ball. - That's...
- His forearm muscles are trained. - Yes.
- That's the throwing pose. - Right.
It's strange. I can't stop looking at his hand.
- Right. - Of course.
Right.
(Blinking)
(I should get up.)
(He makes the bed as soon as he wakes up.)
Hello. I'm a baseball player, Kim Ha Seong.
- He's so handsome. - Gosh, look at the trophy.
(He drinks water as soon as he gets up.)
I'm curious about the house of an MLB player.
You know what I'm curious about?
I'm curious if he can toss the trash...
- into the bin in one go. - If he can make it in one go.
- He must have good aim. - Because he throws baseballs?
He throws baseballs.
- I just put it in the bin. - Are you good at that?
- I don't throw it. - I see.
See? He just puts it in the bin.
You must at least throw your socks...
- into the laundry hamper. - Right.
- Well... - What about your socks?
I take a shower after my games in the US.
The laundry hamper is quite big.
Then I take off my uniform and toss it in the hamper.
- Do they go in then? - They go in, right?
They go in almost every time.
- That's good. - What if you toss them,
and they don't go in?
- What do you do? - I walk over and put them in.
You walk over and put them in?
He'll pick them up.
(Chuckling)
(He plops down with a remote.)
(Clicking)
- What? - Is it automatic?
- What? - What's this?
The skyscraper in Jamsil, L Tower.
- L Tower. - That's Seokchon Lake.
I've been playing baseball in the US for five years.
Whenever I come back to Seoul,
I stay here for about three months during the off-season.
That's so tall.
I get a panoramic view of Seoul.
It overlooks Lotte World and Seokchon Lake too.
I do stay in the US longer,
but Korea feels more like home to me.
I spent more time decorating my house in Korea.
- What a beautiful home. - You got a great home.
It's so neat.
(The sweet home of an MLB player)
How neat.
You're so tidy.
Gosh, your house is really neat.
(Then there's an open view of Seokchon Lake.)
You've kept the uniform for every team you played for.
Yes.
- They're Korean awards. - Yes.
- I won them in Korea. - How fascinating.
(His collection of trophies proves his talent.)
Gosh, he won so many awards.
(Fancy)
(My first hit as a professional player)
What are these baseballs?
Whenever I hit a meaningful milestone,
- my team gives me the ball. - I see. It's written on the ball.
"My first home run as a professional player."
So that's the ball...
- you hit your first home run with. - Yes.
- The ball went over the fence. - How did you get that back?
Did they take it from the fan?
For meaningful milestones...
- like the first home run, - The fans usually return it.
- the fans... Yes. - Do they return the ball?
We give them a signed bat instead.
- I see. You exchange them? - We trade them.
(They exchange the ball with the signed bat.)
Fans usually return the balls.
(On one corner, there's the Gold Glove from the MLB.)
- That's the one from the US. - Yes.
That's his pride.
Kim Ha Seong from San Diego...
("Kim Ha Seong, First Korean to win the Gold Glove in the MLB")
("Kim Ha Seong Makes MLB History")
("First Asian Shortstop in the MLB to Win Gold Glove")
The Gold Glove.
- He's the 1st Asian player. - He's the 1st Asian player.
(Only the Gold Glove winners can have...)
(this gold patch.)
That's so cool.
He didn't win the Gold Glove as a shortstop.
- He won the Gold Glove for Utility. - For Utility.
- He can play any position. - I see.
- He's multi-talented. - He won the award...
- Yes. - for having many talents.
- Being a shortstop is one of them. - Right.
- My gosh. - An award for having many talents?
I used to play shortstop primarily.
But once I went to the US,
I started to play multiple positions.
So you can play all the infield positions, right?
And his batting score was good too.
He's a great shortstop.
- And he's a good batter too. - He's a defensive player...
- who scores too. - Right.
- That's right. - Yes.
What's this gold patch?
Only the Gold Glove winners get this patch.
It's from Rawlings.
- It's like getting a star. - The winners get a patch.
- Only the winners can wear it? - Yes, only the winners can wear it.
- That's the pride. - I wanted to get his autograph,
so I looked up the glove from that brand to buy it.
- It was so expensive. - Really?
- But it's leather. - It's so expensive.
Is there one with faux leather, not real leather?
- Well, - Now...
there must be one with faux leather.
We should implement...
- the three-strike rule. - Right now...
- One strike. - Two fouls.
Is there one with faux leather, not real leather?
- Two fouls. - You said it was expensive.
Two fouls.
What's this sound?
Is that Latin music?
(He plays Latin music in the house.)
(Beating)
When I wake up, I like to listen to Latin music.
After I got to MLB, I met a lot of Latin American players.
Jurickson Profar.
- Fernando Tatis. And Machado. - Tatis.
I'm close to everyone.
There was always Latin music in the clubhouse.
I didn't understand the lyrics.
But Latin music just puts me in a good mood.
It lifts my mood.
Latin music is upbeat too.
(Rummaging through)
(The fridge is well-organized too.)
- It's so neat. - It's well-organized.
Gosh, what's this?
(There are many side dishes too.)
I can see that his mother was there.
(The food pantry is also organized neatly.)
- Look at the alignment. - They're organized perfectly.
- I don't think he cooks. - Me neither.
(He grabs the chicken breast.)
- Chicken breast. - Chicken breast.
(He takes out the protein shake too.)
I guess athletes always have to consume protein.
(Neat)
(The dressing room is organized neatly too.)
That's crazy.
You have a lot of clothes.
(Perfectly folded)
(Perfectly separated by category)
They're organized really neatly.
(Dozens of shoes are neatly placed too.)
- Look at his shoes. - You turned your shoes sideways.
- That makes it easier to see them. - Right.
Yes.
(All of his watches are in a box too.)
- I'm envious of this. - He likes watches.
This is going to excite a lot of watch collectors.
"Gosh, he has all of them?"
- This clip will motivate... - Sure.
- his junior players. - Right.
They will think, "I want to live like that too."
Hard work needs to be rewarded.
It's like giving myself a present.
That's what I had in mind when I bought...
the watches.
(I should wash up.)
(Brushing his teeth)
(After brushing his teeth and washing his face...)
(Crouching down)
(He washes his hair while crouching down.)
(Snorting)
- He sounded like an old man, right? - Yes. Just slightly.
"Snort."
Do you mind if I ask you how old you are?
I was born in 1995.
- You and I are the same age. - In 1995?
- What? You guys are the same age. - Really?
- You're the same age. - Really?
How do people react when you tell them your age?
- Hyun Moo. What do you mean? - What do you mean?
- Listen. - What's that supposed to mean?
I was a bit surprised.
- I... - Because I look older than my age?
It's not that you look older than you age. It's...
Yes.
(He fails to hide his intention.)
Listen. You don't look like you were born in 1995.
- Because he looks quite strong. - It's his presence.
- Right. - He has a big build.
People do this a lot.
I'm sure you played this a lot with your friends too.
Finding celebrities who are the same age as you.
- Right. - Don't you know a few?
I'll start.
- Zo In Sung is the same age as me. - My gosh.
- Lee Dong Wook too. - Oh, no.
I'm also the same age with Gang Dong Won.
Don't you and your friends name celebrities who are the same age?
I don't know a lot of celebrities.
- Really? - That was the third foul.
- That's two outs now. - This is...
Shouldn't this count as an error?
- This isn't my fault. - That's two outs now.
You only have one chance left.
(You only have one chance left.)
(The man born in 1995 washes his hair while crouching down.)
(Bumping)
Gosh, look at his arms.
His arms look really sturdy.
(Muscular arms)
- Gosh. - My gosh.
- Look at that. - Seriously.
- How can his arms be that thick? - He reminds me of Thor.
- Right. - Yes.
(He does a manly skincare routine with his muscular arms.)
That's so cool.
(He returns to the kitchen, clean and refreshed.)
You keep the music on.
(Did it finish thawing?)
(He microwaves the chicken breast first.)
(He makes a protein shake simultaneously.)
(Pouring water to stay hydrated)
(His meal is ready in an instant.)
You should get some tasty food since this is your off-season.
But you're sticking with your diet.
I need to work out right away in the morning.
- I don't want a heavy meal. - He has to work out.
(He starts eating his meal with utensils.)
(He prepares the next protein source while eating protein.)
(Using tongs to grab chicken breast)
(Popping out)
(Oh, no!)
(He quickly puts it in his mouth in 3 seconds.)
Right, he should still eat that.
(He has his meal in silence.)
(He chews his food while spacing out.)
You don't watch any videos.
I'm curious about...
- what he's thinking. - Right.
I think I was just spacing out.
Actually, I didn't know that I spaced out like that.
- After watching the clip... - I just realized that I did.
- Right. - I have no idea...
what you're thinking.
They don't look like tongs. They look like a weapon.
- Right? - Yes, they do.
- It's also his gaze. - I saw that in a film noir movie.
(He's been having chicken breast as breakfast for years and on.)
His gaze is full of testosterone.
(Gold Boy)
- "Gold Boy." - That's scary.
(He munches on the rest of the chicken breast.)
(I'm done.)
(He washes the tongs right away.)
(Gulping down)
(He drinks up the leftover water.)
(He puts away the empty water bottles too.)
(Let me see.)
(He walks over to the neatly organized clothing rack.)
Gosh, he organized his clothes so neatly.
It can't be easy to keep them organized.
(He carefully picks out his outfit.)
I really like clothes.
I especially like tracksuits.
I like tracksuits...
that make you look effortlessly stylish.
I like that kind of tracksuit.
- Effortlessly stylish? - Yes.
- What's this? - You made a lot of effort.
- That's a lot of effort. - Back then...
Is that you in the photo?
It's not.
- It is you. - I'm sorry to ask you this.
- Are you wearing leggings? - Right.
Let me explain. Back then,
- slacks were trending. - Was it several years ago?
That was hip...
- when I was in high school. - Right?
I was following the fashion trend in the US.
- I see. Was it trending in the US? - In the US?
- I guess it was trendy back there. - In the US.
(He wants to look effortlessly stylish.)
- He likes skinny jeans. - I see.
- No. He likes... - Around the ankles.
- skinny jeans. - He likes skinny jeans.
- There's nothing wrong with that. - I'm fine with skinny jeans.
But I can't stand the color.
- The denim wash is infuriating. - It's the denim wash.
- Well... - Isn't that icing blue?
Well, they might not have looked good on me.
- But they're good-quality clothes. - Here's what we have to remember.
We said that there was nothing wrong with the clothes.
- Then my face is the problem? - No.
That's not what I meant.
Bye, Hyun Moo.
There's a fashion style that suits you.
I've lived many years as the worst dresser.
Now that we're watching his clips, I'm seeing a cute side of him...
- I couldn't see at first. - Yes, that's right.
- Right. - He's adorable.
The three photos started...
to make him look cute.
- He's definitely cute. - Yes.
(Opening)
(He opens his watch case.)
(Which one should I wear today?)
I'm the most envious of that.
His outfit won't matter as long as he has one of those.
(Grabbing a bag)
(He's been shaking it for a while now.)
A protein shake.
Actually, it didn't get mixed completely.
I had to drink a chunk of powder.
I had to swallow it.
(There's a chunk of powder.)
(Ha Seong goes out.)
- Gosh. This is your car? - Gosh, what is this?
This is your car? Oh, my.
It's not a crazy expensive car given your annual salary, right?
No, it's crazy expensive.
- Even with your annual salary? - Yes.
I see. It's an expensive car.
(Laughing)
(It's expensive.)
(He goes somewhere in his car.)
(Bobbing)
(As he listens to Latin music, his favorite genre,)
(he's headed somewhere in a good vibe.)
(He arrives at the destination.)
Gosh, it's so cold.
Where is he going?
(He walks over to his destination, shivering from the cold.)
- What? An art gallery? - An art gallery?
Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Where is this place? - I bet it's a sauna spa.
(It's full of workout equipment.)
It must be a gym.
- Gosh. - I knew it.
(A training center)
I go there to work out during my off-season.
Actually, after my season ends,
I always feel like there are more things I can improve on.
So I've been training.
I keep my training light during the season.
But during the off-season, I train harder with weights.
I tend to increase the intensity.
Do you have any sore spots?
They're all over my body. My bottom feels sore.
- And my back too. - Really?
How many hours of sleep did you get?
I slept for 7 to 8 hours.
The session is completely tailored for him.
I don't see any major problems.
(Grabbing)
(He starts with a massage before the workout.)
I see. He's massaging Ha Seong.
Which feels more sore? Your upper or lower body?
- Your lower body? - My lower body.
Let's hold it for ten seconds.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight,
nine, ten.
(Relaxed)
- Gosh, it's so cold today. - Yes.
- It suddenly dropped below zero. - Right.
Should I watch "Zero Dark Thirty?"
(Should I watch "Zero Dark Thirty" since it dropped below zero?)
You like that kind of joke?
He likes it too.
He's faking his reaction. You know?
He has to laugh at your joke.
To hide his face, he looked up and laughed.
(His trainer tilted his head up.)
(It was a good one.)
He's satisfied.
- "Gosh, I was pretty funny." - Yes.
"That was a good one."
- Your right side is stiffer. - My right side?
(Under his meticulous care...)
Okay. Great.
Let's step out.
(His massage is over.)
Come onto your hands and knees on the mat.
Then rotate your shoulders...
ten times each.
Okay.
(Lifting his knees)
You're doing that while lifting your knees?
(Surprised)
(Pressing his lips tightly)
That must be tough.
(He maintains his posture straight and firm.)
It's hot.
Can I take this off?
(He suddenly takes off his shirt.)
He should take it off.
(Now that he takes off a layer of shirt,)
(he moves onto a rotating warm-up with a kettlebell.)
- His arms look great. - Ten each.
Gosh, look at his arms.
Check out his core stability.
That's it. Men must have thick arms.
(These muscles are hard-earned.)
Two.
His forearm muscles...
- are no joke. - Seriously.
Once people see how fit you've become,
they'll say that you've bulked up.
Because I was very skinny in my younger days,
I lacked strength.
- He was different. - He was skin and bones.
- He was so skinny. - So...
(Ha Seong had a small frame in the past.)
With hopes to become stronger,
I bulked up.
(This is how he looks now.)
How much weight did you put on?
I weighed 68kg when I joined the team.
- You were so skinny. - Did you say 68kg?
- I was 20 years old. - His nickname was Thorn.
I wanted to become...
a shortstop who could hit home runs.
Now, I weigh about 90kg.
- You gained over 20kg. - You gained over 20kg.
I'm trying to maintain the weight...
- that gave me the best performance. - You're trying to maintain it.
It's extremely hard for skinny people to bulk up.
- I heard that it was hard. - It's hard.
He put in a lot of effort.
- His body is full of power. - That's right.
(His forearm muscles are working hard.)
(He wraps up the warmup.)
The warmup is over.
(The training begins in earnest.)
- What? - I haven't seen...
that exercise machine before.
(The training begins in earnest.)
- What? - I haven't seen...
that exercise machine before.
It'd be best for you to make the movements...
- that suit your technique. - Is that for pulling?
(He swings it.)
- I see that it's for batting. - Three.
(The movement is similar to batting.)
It's similar.
Five.
The momentary power and speed are important...
in baseball.
So I use weight...
that's heavier than a bat to practice rotation.
- One. - It must be so hard.
Two. Okay.
- What's that? - What's that?
(He throws a ball that's heavier than a bat to practice rotation.)
- Is that the same training? - Yes.
It's for the core and rotation.
(This time, he throws the ball downward!)
He has so much strength.
(Pounding)
Okay.
I'm reminded of what we did.
- Volleyball? - Volleyball.
(They're reminded of the match they had on a rainy day.)
Why were you reminded of that?
- It wasn't similar at all. - Volleyball.
One.
- I hope he comes to the event. - Two.
Three.
- He doesn't get exhausted. - Okay.
It must be because he has good stamina.
How does the training feel?
- It's easy. - "It's easy."
You don't need to do the shoulder exercise...
as often as you did...
during rehabilitation.
You just need to do it lightly once or twice a week.
When I was in San Diego last August,
my shoulder got dislocated.
My shoulder got dislocated during a slide.
I ended up getting surgery.
- Oh, no. - That's insane.
You got injured when your performance was top-notch.
Some people were saying that your career might end...
because the injury was so big.
How did you feel back then?
I wasn't in my right mind.
I bet you wondered if it was the end for you.
I didn't think that.
Foul.
- What? - Foul.
- Foul. - Was it your first foul?
- Back then, I thought I was okay. - Really?
I did a lot of physical therapy,
but I ended up getting surgery.
It was very hard on me.
A shoulder surgery is the biggest deal...
for baseball players.
During rehabilitation, I wondered if I'd be able to return...
and give the same performance...
as I did in the past.
I had a lot of anxiety.
- But I'm in great shape now. - Thank goodness.
It isn't much of physical therapy...
but training for next season.
I'm so thankful...
- that your shoulders got better. - I know.
- Yes. - It's the best news...
for the fans.
Your shoulders are back to normal.
(He puts on new equipment for his shoulders.)
A bit up.
What's that?
What could that be?
When you tighten it, it limits the blood flow.
(It's equipment that limits the blood flow.)
It stresses the muscles...
and increases the blood flow in the arms.
It strengthens the shoulders.
(It increases the efficiency of a light exercise.)
- How many have I done? - His arms turned red.
You're right. They turned red.
How fascinating.
There are all sorts of devices.
The pressure must be great.
- Why is he getting dragged? - He's exhausted.
Why are you coming toward me?
(Inching)
- Little by little... - Step back.
(The major league uses a trick.)
It's my first time seeing him struggle.
- It's my first time. - Yes.
- It must be refreshing. - The blood will flow.
- The blood will flow now. - Yes.
- It feels nice. - When your blood flows.
Is there more?
It's 20kg.
One. Two.
- What? - Is he doing that with 20kg?
Does that vest weigh 20kg?
It's a weighted vest.
He exercises while wearing that vest.
(His muscles bulge.)
(A rubber band in one hand...)
(and an 8kg kettlebell in another)
His shoulders look totally fine...
even in the eyes of non-experts like us.
How does he not grimace?
Seriously. His facial expression doesn't change.
(Even during the off-season, he doesn't stop training.)
Three. A bit more forward.
(His body is in the best condition.)
(He's done warming up for the next season.)
I think you have more strength today.
(He drinks water after exercising.)
It's hard to drink the right amount of water, right?
- I've drunk 2L of water. - What?
- I've drunk 2L of water. - Did he say 2L?
You need to drink a lot of water.
(He has drunk 2L of water in the morning.)
He drinks a lot of water.
Hey, Ju Won, in what year were you born?
- Were you born in 2001? - I was born in 2002.
He's seven years younger.
- He's seven years younger. - Kim Ju Won.
Yes.
He hit a tie-making home run at the end of the ninth inning.
At the end.
We were losing to Japan.
We had 2 outs at the end of the 9th inning.
I had only heard of that situation.
- Yes. - Did he hit a home run then?
Japan's best closing pitcher was on the mound.
He threw the ball well.
He hit a home run.
- Tokyo. - It happened in Tokyo.
He created silence in Tokyo. Complete silence.
(Japan: 7, Korea: 7)
When Ha Seong isn't around,
Ju Won is the shortstop in the national team.
- He has the same position. - The same position.
Yes, he has the same position.
Then you must be Ju Won's role model.
That's right.
- Well, he never told me that. - Didn't he tell you that?
- But I think he respects me. - Of course.
- I'm sure he does. - It's hard to say that...
to your actual role model.
You're right. I think I've told many lies.
Did you have a role model?
I always say that it's Son Pum Soo.
(Joking)
- Come on. - We're close.
He's seven years younger.
That's incredible.
The future of Korean baseball...
is bright.
All done.
Do you exercise like that every day?
Yes. Except on weekends.
(He walks somewhere after exercising.)
(He enters a place.)
- Tuna and fried tofu skin. - He's buying gimbap.
(Tuna and fried tofu skin)
He chose gimbap with a lot of protein.
(He purchases gimbap for lunch after exercising.)
- Tuna and fried tofu gimbap. - Thank you.
(He goes somewhere after buying a roll of gimbap.)
Mr. Kim Ha Seong,
- would you take a selfie with me? - Sure.
Thank you.
My mom is a big fan.
- His mom? - His mom?
I think it came out wrong because he was so startled.
- He went overboard. - Yes.
One, two, three.
(He takes a selfie with his mom's bias.)
- Please be healthy. - Okay.
(Please be healthy!)
He was nervous.
- He was nervous for real. - Seriously.
He must be a big fan.
(Holding a roll of gimbap, he gets into the car.)
Gimbap and Bentley.
It's cold.
- Gimbap and Bentley. - It's a new combination.
It looks different.
- I bet it tastes good in a Bentley. - I know.
(Grabbing)
(Eating gimbap)
(Chewing)
(After eating a piece of gimbap, he drives somewhere.)
(His car gets caught in a red light.)
(Grabbing)
(Inhaling)
He must've been hungry.
- He ate too little for breakfast. - He ate too little.
(The major leaguer eats a roll of gimbap as a meal.)
He likes ballad songs.
(The car stops again.)
(Grabbing again)
(Eating again)
(Stopping once again)
(Eating once again)
He's eating in a hurry.
He must welcome the heavy traffic.
(Thanks to the heavy traffic, he finishes eating inside the car.)
(Grabbing)
(He wraps by drinking water.)
- He's drinking water again. - The bottle doesn't run out of it.
Why do you drink so much water?
Well, water...
(Why does a major leaguer drink so much water?)
(Gulping)
is good for the body.
(I see.)
(Chuckling)
We're getting so many no-nonsense answers today.
I thought a major leaguer would have a special reason.
I thought it was a different type of water.
- We had a fantasy. - That's right.
I expected a scientific reason.
I'll drink some water.
(Everyone drinks water.)
(He sings as he drives.)
(The major leaguer became happy after eating a roll of gimbap.)
His singing skills are...
enough to pass the phone interview of an audition show.
- He'll pass the preliminaries. - That's right.
(He arrives at a parking lot.)
(Opening)
- A bat? - What? It's a bat.
- What? - Will he practice batting?
(He enters a building with a baseball bat.)
(Ha Seong arrives at a place with grass on the floor.)
(It's a training center for baseball techniques.)
It's where I go to train baseball techniques.
He's Coach Jeong Gi Hun.
We've been friends for about 12 years.
We met on an 18U baseball team back in high school.
Whenever I come to Korea during the off-season,
he helps me exercise...
and gives me feedback.
We stay close.
Did he retire?
- Yes. - He retired.
- He retired. - He became a coach.
- Now, - He works as a coach.
he works as a coach.
My main coach who trains me for batting...
is in the US.
But Gi Hun went to US...
and learned from my main coach.
- Then he came to Korea. - That's right.
Thus, their batting mechanisms...
are about the same.
That's why he gives me advice.
- He put a lot of effort into it. - We came up with this arrangement.
(Ha Seong is here to receive advice today as well.)
(He puts on the glove and gets ready for training.)
- Are your hands okay? - Yes.
Don't you need to put on a glove?
Is that catching training?
Yes. It's a part of the routine.
(Training for catching a ground ball)
Four.
(He catches the low ground balls.)
Five.
(He misses the ball.)
It's a miss.
Focus.
- Let's focus. - What?
- A friend can do that. - That's right.
(He changes his pose.)
One.
(He catches the ground balls in a different pose.)
Two. All right.
Three.
(The best friends turn serious during training.)
You try catching the ball in a pose you'd be in during the game, right?
Well, it isn't like that.
- It's just a warmup. - It's just a routine.
- It's just a routine. - Right.
Yes.
- "Right." - One out?
"Right" is an original reaction.
"Right."
(He moves on to the next training.)
Okay.
(When the coach hits a ball with the bat,)
(Ha Seong catches it and throws it back.)
Okay.
(The movement comes in handy during the infield defense.)
Seriously, it's so elegant.
Despite being the second baseman, he goes to the shortstop's area.
The second baseman in the shortstop's area.
That means he was fast.
- That's right. - It's so elegant.
(The coach who jokes around turns serious during training.)
- Return the Golden Glove Award. - What was that?
Return it.
(Let's focus.)
(Rolling)
He missed another one.
(Glaring)
It's because it's a Korean ball.
People praise you too much, but...
Then use an American ball.
- There's an American ball inside. - This is Korean grass.
You have too many excuses. Go.
(Nervous)
Don't blame the tools.
Backhand.
(It goes between his legs.)
It's dangerous.
This ground is bad.
Don't say nonsense like that.
(He adjusts to the bad ground.)
This ground is bad.
(His facial expression turns serious.)
Good. There you go.
- Nice. - Good.
(Come on!)
That's a really hard one.
It looks easy, but it's very hard.
Let's stop.
Are you exhausted?
(Panting)
(The coach sets up a camera.)
What?
(Ha Seong is on the screen.)
I guess there's a machine for analysis.
- Three. - Okay.
(Hitting)
My goodness.
There you go.
The hits are so strong.
(His batting form gets filmed on the monitor.)
(He puts a bar in the middle of the batter's box.)
Is it a part of the routine? What kind of training is this?
It's the batting training.
(Panting)
He's panting already.
Aren't you resting for too long?
You hit one ball and rest.
(He pretends not to hear his coach.)
Hurry up and do it.
(He hits the ball again.)
Okay.
(Hitting)
The sound changed.
How does he hit it like that?
(He hits it like this.)
- It sounds like a gun. - Okay.
- His swing is so satisfying. - Nice.
- He doesn't even rest. - He hit the ball well just now.
That was great.
(I'll monitor my performance.)
(Let's see.)
- He'll monitor his performance. - His batting form.
You stride forward during the game, but...
- The distance between the legs? - Yes.
(That's what he means by a stride.)
I'm sure the physicality is different,
but there's a difference of 10 to 20 degrees.
I think you can move forward more and split your legs more.
Do you agree with that?
- Do you agree with that? - No.
Isn't it because of his big build?
After I moved from Korea to the US,
I changed my batting form...
- little by little. - That's right. You changed it.
Even though I work in the US,
many people give me advice.
I accept them with gratitude.
I agreed with what he said about my stride.
I agreed that I needed to step forward more.
- You needed to step forward - When you hit the ball?
I really didn't move forward when I hit the ball.
- You stayed still. - Yes.
- I agreed with that. - It helped.
He gives me such key points.
I bet you're saying this because you felt bad.
(Seeing how you're talking about it)
Increase the number little at a time.
You should hit the right number of balls.
You need to decide the number.
(He cleans up after practice right away.)
(He picks up 4 balls with 1 hand.)
(He cleans up fast with his big hands.)
Earlier, I saw...
that baseball players had calluses in this part of their hands.
Is it because of the bat?
- Yes. Here. - Look.
- I've never seen calluses here. - I know.
- You're right. - He has calluses here.
He has calluses here.
- I see. - Let me see them.
It's raised.
(Proud)
It's like my mom's foot.
- Why would you say that? - You're such a bad son.
Are your mom's feet that hard?
(Fidgeting)
I'm going now.
(With his tiger-like coach who is also his best friend,)
(he had an hour-long technique training.)
(Ha Seong goes somewhere again.)
- Is it a supermarket? - It's a supermarket.
It's a supermarket.
Maybe he'll get all the chicken breasts.
I think he'll eat pork and beef.
It must be here.
Cucumbers.
(He puts a bag of cucumbers in his cart.)
He's buying unpeeled onions.
(He gets ingredients without hesitation.)
What will he cook?
(He stops his cart in front of Korean beef.)
Thin flank.
(Picking up)
Six packs for one person?
I bet he eats a lot.
I bet he does.
(He finishes paying.)
It's hot.
My goodness.
(He puts the bag on the table.)
(He brings the clothing bag to the bedroom.)
(Rummaging)
- What is he doing? - What is that?
- Salt? - Yes, it's salt.
- Salt? - Why are you doing that?
I was told to wash it like that.
- Did your mom tell you that? - Yes. So I just do that.
(His muscles bulge.)
(He shakes off the water with his forearm muscles...)
(that brought him the Golden Glove Award.)
(Focused)
(He scores the inside...)
(to remove the seeds with precision.)
Why do you remove the seeds? Do you not like them?
If I keep the seeds, the dish turns watery.
- Because it turns watery? - Yes.
There we go.
(He finishes preparing cucumbers.)
(He prepares an onion as well.)
I see that you cook for yourself.
I enjoy cooking. I think it's fun.
- Really? - Do you cook?
Do you cook in the US?
Yes.
I love Korean food a lot.
(Pouring)
(He adds different ingredients to gochujang with ease.)
Minced garlic, chili powder, gochujang...
(Sniffing)
- It looks tasty. - That's ready.
He adds the whelk soup.
(He adds all the solid ingredients.)
(It's time to mix.)
With the hands that won the Gold Glove Award...
The golden whelks.
(I'll give the world-class mixing.)
My goodness.
The whelks look delicious.
(This is the taste.)
It looks tasty.
(He adds the ingredients as he sees fit.)
He must be used to cooking.
(He makes eyeball measurements.)
(He pours bone broth.)
(It smells good.)
Someone is coming.
He isn't eating alone.
(Who came to Ha Seong's place?)
Who is it?
(Ha Seong is cooking alone.)
Someone is coming.
He isn't eating alone.
Who is it?
(Two people punch in the password and walk in.)
- There is another one. - There are two people.
What's up?
- Did they punch in the password? - What's up, dude?
Yes, they know the password.
- What are you doing? - Why did you come back?
- We saw each other earlier. - It's the friend we saw earlier.
You're right. The friend who's a coach.
(The tiger-like coach didn't allow the smallest mistake.)
(Gi Hun is a best friend who trains and eats with him.)
- He's a best friend. - Do you need help?
(Another friend has come with Gi Hun.)
- Who said it was fine? - Run!
The second base.
He gets taken out at the second base.
I see. He's Kim Jae Hyun.
Yes.
(Kim Jae Hyun, Kim Ha Seong)
- Is that you? - That's right.
They were on the same team.
(The three of them became close through baseball.)
So, are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
I'm about to die.
Did you see that?
Yes.
It's wearing clothes too.
(Fascinated)
- Have you seen it before? - It's my first time.
It resembles you a bit.
(Taking out)
- I need to be paler for that. - Wilson.
(He takes out water and drinks it naturally.)
(He walks over somewhere.)
How many Cheongyang peppers should I add?
Three? Two?
(He enters the dressing room.)
- Two. - Two.
They have the best friends' vibes.
He even wanders around the house. It's perfect.
Shall I add one more Cheongyang pepper?
You're going to add it anyway.
I forgot to buy tofu.
What else did you add? MSG?
- I'm not going to add it. - You always add it.
What are you saying?
Isn't this security camera footage?
There's no meaning.
(Embarrassed)
- There are no pleasantries. - There are no pleasantries.
They just say what they want to say.
I love it.
- It's like security camera footage. - I love it.
Hey, get ready to eat now.
- Do you need help? - What?
- Do you need help? - Get ready to eat.
(What do I need to do?)
What is it?
- Where is it? - Come here.
I want you to do this.
(He readily walks over to help.)
Shall I mix everything?
(He mixes everything without a complaint.)
I need a trivet under the soup.
(He prepares it right away.)
Shall we scoop some out on our plates?
Scoop out the amount you want.
There's a lot.
(The tiger-like coach has become a docile sheep.)
At home, he's just a friend. He isn't a coach.
That's right.
(Thanks to the friends' help)
You made a lot of food.
- I'll start grilling meat now. - Okay.
That kimchi jjigae looks tasty.
The color of the kimchi jjigae tells me that it's tasty.
(Beef will fill their stomachs.)
- It looks tasty. - Whelks.
Whelks look tasty.
(Ha Seong's Korean meal is complete.)
Eat up.
(The man who cooked, Ha Seong, takes a bite first.)
(Humming in approval)
(He rips kimchi with his hands!)
(Sucking)
(He wraps white rice with it and stuffs his mouth.)
It must be tasty.
(His two friends eat without any words.)
There isn't a lot of meat.
They must've been hungry.
The one who cooked...
must be worried about their silence.
Yes.
- It's tasty. - It's tasty.
- It's hot. - The kimchi is nice.
It's tasty.
- The reactions are nice. - He pretends not to hear them.
It's high praise.
It's insanely hot.
Would you turn on the air conditioner?
It's hot. Would it be okay if I changed into new clothes?
It's a men's conversation.
The air conditioner is on.
- It's on. - Why are you wearing comfy clothes?
(Jae Hyun goes somewhere.)
Does it smell strongly of meat?
No.
It's nice.
- Is that my T-shirt? - Yes.
Did you pick a white T-shirt to wear during the meal?
- Yes. I spotted it first. - Did you have to do that?
There are many black T-shirts.
No, there aren't. I didn't see them.
- Hey, come here. - He's going to change.
I need to change.
Hey, wear a black top.
Gi Hun.
If you pick an expensive one, you won't be able to wear it home.
(Dumbfounded)
- I found it. - He wore a white T-shirt.
(He wore a white T-shirt like Jae Hyun.)
- Of course. - He did it on purpose.
He should've worn new pants as well.
Food particles and oil are bound to get on...
the T-shirt.
(This is great.)
(He can't believe his eyes.)
Gi Hun, sprinkle some salt.
You haven't had surgery either, right?
In high school, I had one.
He had ankle surgery.
(Salt doesn't come out.)
Is it coming out? For goodness' sake.
(Timid)
- Am I doing it wrong? - Is it yours?
It's new.
(What?)
(Not knowing what's wrong, he keeps turning it.)
- Gosh. - Open it and remove the seal.
- Open it? - It's new, right?
- No way. - It has to be new.
(The opening is sealed.)
- Why are you so dumb? - You...
(Dying of laughter)
(Embarrassed)
When friends gather around,
the atmosphere stays the same...
whether the location is your house or a resort.
- You're right. - Right?
I find it so hilarious that they're at L Tower.
I thought that to myself as well.
- It's a guest house in Yangpyeong. - An Airbnb in Yangpyeong.
(It's a guest house in Yangpyeong.)
Right. It seems like it.
- It has to make a grinding sound. - It has to be opened first.
Are you sure?
It has to be opened first.
You were doing it confidently as if you knew how to use it.
I thought you were struggling to use it.
Gosh, I'm sweating all of a sudden.
Let's say you get...
a good offer right away tomorrow.
Do you have to head to the US right away?
Yes.
But I don't know what to do right now.
Do you have any thoughts about retiring in Korea?
I'm curious about that.
If Kiwoom Heroes asks me to come back?
What if they will ask you to come back no matter what?
Then I must come back.
Are you thinking about ending your career in Korea?
Yes.
Your seniors, Park Chan Ho and Kim Byung Hyun,
- did the same. - Right.
- They came back to Korea. - Ryu Hyun Jin.
Ryu Hyun Jin and Choo Shin Soo.
Right.
As I played for Kiwoon Heroes,
- I was able to make it to the US. - Right.
I want to play with them before I end my career.
(A heart of wanting to end his career with them out of gratitude)
I want to play with Ha Seong before my career ends.
We were on the same team for seven years.
But we weren't able to...
play together as much.
I just clapped from the dugout.
I must've done well...
- because you did that. - Right.
Jae Hyun was like a mentor to me starting from a young age.
He must have supported him a lot mentally.
(Peeking)
Still, Jae Hyun was in the same team with you.
(Feeling jealous)
You were jealous that we were on the same team, right?
- We were all together. - Right.
I was the only one to play for a different team.
Ha Seong, Jae Hyun,
Ji Yeol, and Jung Hoo.
All four of you were on the same team.
Right. Why didn't you work hard?
He's getting at him.
That was why I went down to the reserves.
(He makes his response lightly.)
But after all that,
you're living a better second act of your life now.
So I'm saying...
- there's a time for everything. - There's a set schedule.
- Everyone has their moment. - Right. That's a great line.
I wouldn't have dreamt of becoming a coach...
if it wasn't for him.
- What would you have done? - I'm being honest.
After being released from the team,
I drank every single day.
I drank and cured my hangover over and over.
I contacted him one day.
It was the first year he went to the US.
- During my first year... - He had a hole in his head.
He lost so much hair.
I called him and said I was struggling.
Around 30 to 40 minutes later,
he sent me a plane ticket.
He said,
- "Come to the US tomorrow." - That's impressive.
The plane was scheduled to set off at 7pm the next day.
- That was the schedule. - He's so impressive.
He said, "Think that you're visiting Jeju Island for a week."
I just brought three pairs of shorts and T-shirts with me.
I extended my stay 3 times and stayed for 3 months.
I got rid of my clothes and borrowed his clothes...
to stay for three months.
Did you call him because you were bored?
- No. - No. I'm sure that wasn't it.
I felt so lonely,
and I struggled so much at that time.
So I just went,
"Let's not struggle separately."
"Let's struggle together."
I wasn't picked to play all the time as well,
so I asked him to come and talk with me.
Do you know what the important part is?
I was with him for around ten days.
He had to be away for two weeks for away games.
All he left with me was his credit card.
"Order food with this."
He took a plane and left after that.
I was left alone in San Diego just like that.
I didn't even know how to make an order at a restaurant.
That was how I stayed alone for two weeks.
(The true Korean waited for Ha Seong desperately for 2 weeks.)
I comforted him so much.
I truly did.
He said this.
"Jae Hyun,"
"Ohtani said he must be lonely to do well."
"Let's be strictly lonely and not contact each other."
(All of a sudden?)
I saw Ohtani do an interview.
He said he must only focus on baseball.
His head must be filled only with baseball.
He said he had to be strictly lonely to succeed.
You gain strength when you are in solitude.
But without lying one bit about this,
a news article about his marriage was released.
("Shohei Ohtani Reveals Sudden Marriage Announcement")
This actually happened?
This actually happened.
Really?
He was lying!
Ohtani was seeing someone too.
Right.
So he meant being lonely as an athlete.
Does he call you Mr. Kim?
- He doesn't call me Mr. Kim. - He doesn't call you Mr. Kim?
- He just... - Kim?
Right. Kim.
He says "hello" in Korean.
- Ohtani? - Yes.
- He speaks in Korean? - Yes.
He says "hello" in Korean.
And I go, "Konnichiwa."
Or if it's past 6pm,
- I go, "Konbanwa." - "Konbanwa."
You're precise.
I had to pay him back with respect.
That was a great meal, Ha Seong.
Thank you for that, Ha Seong.
You're welcome.
(Let's clean up since we had a great meal.)
I wiped it once.
They're cleaning up together.
(Wiping)
(They clean up in no time as the three work together.)
(The night deepens with their friendship.)
The left wall!
- The left wall by the tree! - "The left wall?"
- Let's jump together. - What?
They went to an Internet cafe?
There he is!
Kim Ha Seong at an Internet cafe?
(The Major Leaguer appears at an Internet cafe.)
- Okay. We advanced. Ball! - Short! Ball!
The color of the headphones is awesome.
- Watch the short side. - Ball!
The 3mm gap between the containers.
- Look at his eyes. - Don't move out.
- Look at his eyes. - I don't play at all in the US.
When it's off-season,
- With your friends? - I play with my friends.
I'm the best player in that area.
Which game do you play?
- Sudden Attack? - Yes.
- What's your rank? - I'm a Brigadier General.
- You're a Brigadier General? - A One Star.
Does that mean he's good?
He's really high up if he's a Brigadier General.
It's a top rank.
- He must be really good. - Recently,
I haven't been doing so bad.
I didn't do so bad during the rank matches.
He sounds more passionate than when talking about baseball.
(He sounds more passionate than when talking about baseball.)
(He clicks on the mouse with passion.)
Okay!
- What? - Nice.
Hey, jump to the right!
Jump! Move to the short side.
Both of you should go in.
- Look at how focused they are. - They're really into it.
(They're all very focused.)
Where is he?
(He gets competitive even in a game as a professional baseball player.)
He looks even more serious than when playing baseball.
Ever since I was ten as an elementary school student,
I only played baseball until the age of 31.
I don't recall myself doing anything else.
During the ten months spent in the US,
I only played baseball.
Every single day is a time of war in the US.
- Gosh. - I'm busy trying to survive.
I get around three months back in Korea.
I can spend this time for myself during these three months.
- It's a very important time. - I can meet friends...
and family.
It's a time when I can prepare myself...
to do much better for the upcoming season.
- Ball! - They're coming.
It's great to see him look happy.
(Ha Seong's team wins.)
- Did you see my reflexes? - That was nice.
(Feeling proud)
(Chuckling)
Jump, Jae Hyun! They came in from the left wall!
(A Nice Catch for a Happy Daily Life)
- That was great. - Gosh!
We were able to see his different charms.
When he plays baseball,
- he doesn't show much expression. - Right.
We didn't know what kind of life he lived.
But after watching this, I realized he's a lot like us.
Right, he's like us.
This is one of the attitudes I wish to possess.
The attitude of someone who just does things.
(Giving things a try right away)
Many athletes who made great achievements...
tend to have this attitude.
"Why did you do this?"
"Just because."
- Without a specific purpose. - Right.
It was impressive as I saw many of those moments from him.
- He just went to an Internet cafe. - Right.
Are you down for a game when you come during off-season?
- Sounds good. - Let's play together.
I'll let you play if you're good.
(He's strict when it comes to competition.)
Are you on the same level as him?
Well, I can always practice.
- What's your rank? - I can practice consistently.
It's just like riding a bike.
- I'll consistently work on it. - Right.
I'll show you the value of consistency.
Sounds great.
Could you tell us about your plans ahead?
I will be heading back to the US at around the middle of January.
I will prepare myself well during off-season...
and make sure to show my fans...
some good baseball.
I do want to watch a baseball game.
You'll fall right into it.
You won't be able to get out once you get into it.
You have to go to a baseball park.
- Right. - You have to go to a baseball park.
To be honest, you can watch soccer just on TV.
That's not true.
You have to go to a ball park for baseball.
- People have been telling me that. - That's true.
- We should go and watch him play. - That would be amazing.
Let's go.
Right. You should all feel comfortable...
- to come. - Really?
- We'll really go. - Sure.
No matter what team you join,
- we will support that team. - Right.
Feel comfortable to come.
- I will really support you there. - Sure.
- We should really go. - With that said,
always be careful not to get injured,
and we wish that you will join a team that you wish for...
- with a great deal. - Right.
- Thank you. - You're at the age...
when baseball players experience their second prime.
- The early 30s. - Right.
We will be excited to see you...
experience another prime next season.
- Thank you. - Great.
We will root for your golden days to come!
- Let's go! - Let's go!
(I Live Alone)
- "The Master of Masters?" - "The Master of Masters?"
(KEY heads somewhere.)
(Naegok-ri, Namyangju)
Where is Naegok-ri?
(Past the friendly-looking area,)
(he arrives somewhere.)
Why does he have so many things?
(He moves with a lot of things.)
Where is this?
(It's me.)
- Hello! - Hello!
(Gosh!)
(They get startled by her voice.)
- Kany! - Gosh!
(Dizzy)
(Kany recognized Ju Seung during their first encounter...)
(as the one in the drama.)
The bad guy.
(Yes. I'm the bad guy.)
Thank you.
(They introduced themselves to each other with confidence.)
(I'm a beautiful older girl.)
(But he felt totally overwhelmed by Kany's energy.)
Get yourself together, Ju Seung!
He got traumatized by her.
- Gosh! - He's feeling low on sugar already.
- Gosh! - Hello!
- Hello! - Welcome!
- My goodness! - Hi!
- Hi! - Welcome!
- Have you been doing well? - Yes.
You came all the way here. Gosh.
- Finally! - Finally!
- Finally. - You two have finally met.
- Hello, ma'am. - Welcome!
- Who is she? - Who is she?
It's my friend Kany...
and her mother-in-law.
This was how things started.
I wanted Kany to get along with her mother-in-law better,
so I made them kimchi and dumplings.
That sparked this moment.
(Kany's mother-in-law made delicious side dishes in return.)
(You got more kimchi from her than I did.)
She sends me so many side dishes.
(Se Yoon tried the kimchi made by Kany's mother-in-law.)
(It was made by my friend's mother-in-law!)
(The mother-in-law of Kany, my black dancer)
(Shocked again)
That's a rare moment to be able to...
try the kimchi of a friend's mother-in-law.
(Big Eater Se Yoon approved of the master's kimchi.)
I've only met her briefly before.
- I'll get you something to drink. - No.
I'll help.
- Help her, daughter-in-law. - No.
- It's fine. - She seems a bit calmer.
Right.
Hello!
- This is just a simple snack. - Gosh!
(Kany's mother-in-law brought out some snacks for KEY.)
Gosh, thank you. I haven't had anything yet today.
- This feels exciting already. - I see.
How did you...
Hold on, ma'am.
(This!)
Back then, you gave me these.
- Gosh. - These are your containers...
- and some other gifts in return. - Come on.
- Why bother to bring these? - The containers she sent?
- Right. - I prepared more side dishes.
- Again? - Yes.
Really? I want some too!
- She's bringing them out. - Gosh.
They're too heavy to lift up.
She gave me twice as more.
It already looks like a lot.
This is the chili jangajji.
You can still eat it even though it's not fully fermented.
- If you wait a bit longer... - Wait!
The chili jangajji and seasoned bellflower roots.
- This is the garlic jangajji. - That and white rice...
Gosh, I can't even speak properly.
- That's so good. - Right.
This is the godeulppaegi kimchi.
- Gosh, am I allowed to take this? - Wait!
I brought something for you as well.
- Really? - I brought something...
- Oh, really? - for her.
- I'm excited. - The box was too big,
so I brought them without the box.
I've tried using these.
- Are these leg massagers? - Yes.
- Gosh! - This one.
This one is shaped like a fork.
- Oh, my gosh! - It works like this.
Just like this.
- Mothers love those. - Gosh.
(The daughter-in-law loves it as well.)
It's nice, isn't it?
The daughter-in-law loves it even more.
- It feels great. - We will be making kimchi today.
It'll be for the family. Are you really going to help?
- Yes. Of course. - Gosh.
We collect the ingredients from the garden.
There will be a lot of things to do.
They collect all of the ingredients from the garden.
- The vegetable garden? - Yes.
- I tried making kimchi. - Gosh, that goes a while back.
(He even made oyster radish kimchi...)
(and captured Kany's appetite.)
(He swiftly made a large kimchi dish as well.)
- You got some of that as well. - That was really good.
As I only received things from her,
I wanted to return her the favor.
I decided to help her out with kimchi making,
and I also wanted to learn the secret of her great kimchi.
That was why I decided to visit.
- Let's get changed, - Right.
- so that we can work diligently. - Okay.
That's such a fascinating relationship.
Right?
(Laughing)
Right.
It feels like space and time are distorted.
(That's how fascinating it is.)
Right?
- Let's head out to the garden now. - Right.
Go out and do a lot of work today.
- It sounds exciting. - It does, doesn't it?
I have never done this before.
Will I be able to do this?
Will I be able to do this, Mom?
(Her heart pounds as it's her first time making kimchi.)
- Is everything there? - Yes.
Gosh, they're holding hands.
- My goodness. - The weather is so nice!
This must be it.
- Here. - Really?
- Be careful, Mom! - I'm fine.
- Are you okay? - Gosh!
- This is it. - Gosh!
It's a vegetable garden right next to the apartment complex.
Let's take a look.
It's quite big.
(It's full of crops that will be used for kimchi.)
She's a rich farmer.
- She doesn't own the whole area. - Is that so?
Parts of the garden must be owned by different people.
Yes, that's right.
What should we start with? This
The radishes must be collected and sorted out.
These are the ones that will be used for the kimchi filling.
They're totally organic.
How many of these are needed?
- These? Around 15? - How many?
- Around 15? - Around 15?
There are some at home.
- Three, oh! - Okay.
And four, oh!
- And 5, oh! - And 5, oh!
- Kany is bringing up her energy. - And six, oh!
- And 7, oh! - And 7.
And eight, oh!
Hey! And eight, oh!
You feel energized when there's a friend like Kany.
And 12, oh!
Thirteen, oh!
- No more! - Fourteen, oh!
- She looks exhausted. - We need only 15. Stop!
- That's 15. - That's enough!
These should be moved over there.
Collect the big ones from here.
The big ones?
(He watches the master demonstrate.)
- Like that? - Yes.
You two are doing well at your first attempts.
- Well, I had my own garden too. - Right.
(Their hands get used to the garden work.)
One person should pick out the radish like this.
- Right. - Right. Gosh.
The rest will sort the radishes out.
- Gosh. - Just do it like this.
It's really easy. Okay.
Oh, my gosh.
(The young radish is picked out swiftly.)
- Gosh. - Your legs.
- My back. - Sit here and do it.
I told you I had a disc problem.
- Oh, yes. - Kany can't have her legs crossed.
- Do it slowly. - Right.
- It will be exhausting. - Yes!
I like it!
Right? Sit down and work.
(Sitting down)
It's nice as the weather is great, isn't it?
- It's wonderful. - It's wonderful.
Everything looks fascinating.
It's a stress-reliever.
- Like so and so. - Right.
Gosh, this one is big!
- These parts must be sorted out. - Wait.
- Hold on. - This is good enough, right?
- Yes. - This isn't too small, right?
You're good at this.
(Carving)
Kany!
Okay. Like this.
Is this okay?
- So this is what Mother did. - Okay.
Think of this as a sample.
- This is what she did. - Okay.
Oh, no. Well, yes.
(She finally puts in one.)
Do it quick!
(She quietly picks up the radish Kany worked on.)
(She works on it again without Kany knowing.)
I love doing that. I think I have a talent.
I'm serious.
Are you going to switch jobs?
Are you going to stay with me now?
This is so much fun. Why is this so fun to do?
- Are you having fun? - Yes!
It felt awkward just at the start. You're loving it here now, right?
Father was so shy.
He's really introverted.
He must've felt awkward at first.
I heard he talks about Kany at work as well.
He says he got a good daughter-in-law.
I know.
- He boasts about you. - Really?
He says a lot of good things about you at work.
She's worth boasting about.
- Mom! - Yes?
- From now on, - Yes?
- I will visit often. - Will you help me out often?
- Really? - Will you come to help me?
She's so cute.
(I'm so grateful.)
What will we eat today?
Today? Bossam.
Oyster bossam!
- What? - Yes.
- She loves oyster bossam. - Really?
I must make you your favorite.
- That's your favorite. - I love you, Mom.
- Okay. Let's make it quick! - Let's hurry!
- Let's hurry! - Let's hurry!
(Singing gibberish)
(Mulkimchi!)
(This rhythm feels familiar.)
(Your irresistible spell)
(Mulkimchi)
This is it.
- It was this song? - No wonder it sounded familiar!
Mulkimchi, in freedom
(Singing gibberish)
She's doing whatever she wishes to with my song.
(Radish mic)
So that's what it sounds like to her?
(Scraping)
(Her hands move quickly with the mulkimchi song beat.)
There's even more work to do.
They're picking up the pace.
Gosh, I love her energy.
They worked on a lot of them.
- Mom! - Yes?
I worked on all of these.
- Great job! - Great job!
You're the best!
Come and work on these as well.
- Okay. These are done. - Right.
(They collected the ingredients for around two hours.)
- Gosh! - Great work.
(Gosh!)
- Do you feel exhausted? - I'm fine.
You feel okay?
We still have a lot more to do.
Where else can you find a daughter-in-law like that?
Making kimchi is tough, even when the ingredients are bought.
- They all have to be worked on. - Don't worry. It's okay.
It's okay. We'll have oyster bossam.
(They're done harvesting. They'll start making kimchi now.)
Oh, boy. What do we do? We need to hurry up.
We should move them to the veranda.
- To the veranda? Okay. - Yes.
- The napa cabbage are salted. - How many heads are they?
Oh, my. It looks like a side dish store.
(The plastic basins are filled with salted napa cabbage.)
That's a lot.
When she makes kimchi alone,
she uses 50 or 60 heads of napa cabbage.
Then did you make more kimchi than that?
We used 70 heads of napa cabbage.
(Amazed)
These napa cabbage are in a different color, right?
- Yes, they're yellow. - Right.
These are not regular napa cabbage.
They're tastier and more refreshing.
- That's why they're yellow. - Yes. They look different, right?
It's a different type of napa cabbage.
The napa cabbage we know...
has stems, the white part, in the center.
And the leafy part is light yellow...
or green. You can see a gradient of those colors.
But most of the leafy part of this type was yellow.
The yellow type tastes good.
She grew the napa cabbage by herself.
She said that a small amount of salt was enough...
to salt napa cabbage...
if you salted them for two days.
And that makes kimchi taste even better.
The napa cabbage absorb the kimchi sauce well too.
- Oh, I didn't know that. - I see.
They do look different from the ones in stores.
- They're different. - It feels different.
- They're salted well. - It's tasty as it is.
- It's not too salty. - The saltiness must be just right.
Shall we make dried pollack porridge?
- Dried pollack porridge? - Yes.
Dried pollack porridge.
Dried pollack porridge?
We use dried pollack to make kimchi.
Kany.
Can you wash the radish...
in front of the salted cabbage?
Okay.
Put these on when you're out there.
- Oh, okay. - Be sure your feet don't get wet.
- Okay. - Okay. Be careful.
- Kany. - Yes?
I know you can do it.
(Rubbing)
Oh, that's fun.
Fun!
(She finds Kany cute.)
A, the, wash it
Wash it
Come on, radish
(While washing the radish, she starts singing cheerfully again.)
Wash the radish, all right
(Oh, my. Kany never lets me down.)
(KEY comes back to the kitchen to make dried pollack porridge.)
Dried pollack porridge?
(He looks around the kitchen of the master in fascination.)
That was really fascinating. I'd never seen it before.
I use this to add sweetness.
- You add jujube. - Yes.
(She adds dried shiitake mushroom as well.)
(Taking dried pollack out)
Now, the dried pollack...
You don't make rice flour paste?
I'll put the paste in the porridge.
- You'll add it to the porridge? - Yes.
- She sounds like a kimchi master. - Exactly.
(Thinking)
Is this a family recipe?
- No, it isn't. - No?
- I invented my own recipe. - You invented it?
Yes, I did.
- And it turned out great. - Right. Your kimchi was very tasty.
Other people say my kimchi is good.
I guess she made her own recipe from her experience.
- So she didn't learn that. - She invented the recipe.
- She invented the recipe. - Yes.
Three would be enough for one pot.
(Getting closer to her)
So you remove those parts.
(I can't miss any step of the process.)
(She puts the cleaned dried pollack in the water.)
The fish will bend when the water gets hot.
Oh, my. This is very unique.
(Jujube, shiitake mushroom, onion, kelp, garlic, ginger)
She uses many different ingredients.
(Now they're waiting until the broth is ready.)
- Oh, my. - What?
It looks like a swimming pool.
- It looks like a swimming pool. - A swimming pool?
Yes.
(Acting like she's swimming)
Now we should put on gloves.
We should put on a hat and everything, right?
Here you go, Kany.
- Yes. - Yes?
(Hygiene is essential.)
(They put on hygienic cooking hats...)
(and masks.)
(Clean and hygienic)
Now we'll use the porridge...
- We'll use the porridge. - Yes.
Is this salt?
It's glutinous rice flour. I'll mix it with water.
Okay.
(Stirring)
Oh, is it done?
(The glutinous rice paste goes into the dried pollack porridge.)
- In the broth you made earlier? - Pour it all.
We put it in the broth.
- It became sticky. - Right.
It must be. Now we should bring it to a boil.
I see.
- Making kimchi is like... - It's like a whole... Yes.
It's like a whole journey.
You can do it
- Come on - Good. Kany's singing...
helps it boil faster.
See? It's coming... It's going to start boiling quickly.
Come on
(The daughter-in-law starts singing a work song.)
(Smiling happily)
Hey, come on, come on
(Tapping rhythmically)
The density is perfect.
- This is why you call it porridge. - That's right.
The density is just right.
Oh, my. The color is fascinating.
I'm the master of making this.
- What was that? - Mama is the best.
What is that?
(A mysterious machine appears?)
Good.
(She keeps bringing equipment even after that.)
If you put it in here, it will fall on the mat.
- Oh, my. Look at that. - She has a lot of equipment.
(Looking carefully)
I'll do that.
- You have to press it with this. - Got it.
(Amazed)
Oh, my.
You can julienne radish like that?
- I can do it from here. - Okay.
That's easy work.
- You just have to put it in. - Okay.
- Now press it. - Oh, my.
- It juliennes vegetables. - Is there such a machine?
That's awesome.
It's like a meat grinder at a butcher shop.
Right, the machine at a butcher shop.
- Okay! - I love this work.
- Yes. - It's fun, isn't it?
- People used a slicer before. - Right, they used a slicer.
That's amazing.
(The amazing slicer)
Men, use tools.
(Pressing hard)
Oh, you have to press? Okay, I'll press it.
- Now you're doing well. - I'll press it.
Press it, press it, Girl, press it, press it
(Her excitement is at the maximum level.)
(KEY is also fully satisfied.)
I love it.
(While pressing it with the cheery energy...)
We're done with the radish.
My, they use a lot of radish.
It's not peeled.
(She uses a slicer to julienne a pear?)
Other people make juice out of pears.
- But I just... - You julienne them.
The strips fall apart over time.
- They're soft. So... - Only the refreshing taste is left.
Right. That's why I don't make juice.
As the pear softens over time,
the radish absorbs its sweetness.
And that makes kimchi better, according to her.
- Rather than adding sugar? - Yes.
You can just put some on top of the radish.
- It will fall on the mat. - Right.
- Just chop them like this... Yes. - I just have to chop them?
- Like this. - Oh, okay. Got it.
I find it hard to believe that this came from the field.
I'm really grateful.
The farmer's love.
(And the mother's technique)
This is fun.
She works really fast.
She's the best.
It's because she's done it so many times before.
(KEY works hard to chop it next to her.)
It's done.
How did she do it all by herself?
Exactly. How did she do it all by herself?
She's like an artisan. She's the kimchi master.
(That's what makes someone a master.)
- We should add the sauce, right? - We should mix it with the sauce.
I can mix it with the sauce.
I'll go and bring the sauces.
Okay.
(Cutting)
He's working hard quietly.
- In here? - Spread it evenly.
Like that? Okay.
(Pouring)
Here goes chili powder.
(The cheery energy is a bonus.)
Look at the chili powder.
(The red chili powder covers the vegetables.)
Here. Pour the whole bottle in here.
- What is that, ma'am? - It's juice of salted shrimp.
I see.
- Salted shrimp. - Just the juice, not the shrimp.
- Just the juice, not the shrimp? - Right.
This is plum extract.
- She adds plum extract too? - That's a common ingredient.
This is salted anchovy.
- Anchovy juice. - Pour it.
(Focused)
(While preparing the young radish...)
(Glancing)
What is that?
Do it like this.
(Now that everything is in here, we should mix them together.)
You're quick at doing this.
(While glancing at them,)
(KEY quietly prepares the radish staying at the same spot.)
- I just worked hard quietly. - That's great.
That's a lot.
You look like a factory worker.
Now I'll add the porridge we made.
(The kimchi master's key ingredient completes the sauce.)
- She uses no store-bought products. - That's right.
She made each and every ingredient.
Oh, my. She's really incredible.
I see no store-bought products.
Oh, dear. It's done.
(They made kimchi filling with natural ingredients.)
My, look at the filling.
- It looks good. - It looks really good.
(Pushing)
(He washes young radish without being asked.)
That's a lot. They'll make kimchi with all that?
There are so many things to do.
(He even removes water thoroughly.)
He's good at it.
- I think I'm done. - Okay.
All right. Let's cook the meat first.
(It's already 10 to 6.)
(Reaching for the cabbage)
(Watch closely.)
Put it only on the stem.
(The kimchi master's secret: Put the filling only on the stem.)
(He scans the kimchi once.)
She does everything thoroughly.
It shouldn't be just red.
It shouldn't be too red.
(Pressing)
Look at that. She's really fast.
She's really fast.
(Rubbing)
(KEY speeds up to catch up with the master.)
It was my first time making that much kimchi at once.
I shouldn't be doing this.
(KEY finished one head as well.)
Big ones are done more quickly.
Ma'am, how do I wrap this?
With the outermost leaf.
Yes. Fold it first.
So that the filling doesn't fall out.
- Oh, that's why. - Yes.
Like this, right?
- I should put the filling on it. - Yes.
Okay. We can do it.
Yes!
Let's do this!
(We've got this!)
(With a shout,)
(they cheer up to make all napa cabbages red.)
(Kimchi, kimchi, ya, ya, ya)
(We'll make kimchi with all of those?)
This is really...
(Gasping)
(More)
(The more napa cabbages are brought, the less they speak.)
(They even season their clothes too.)
- Look at her clothes. - I got it all over my clothes.
- It happens with no exception. - I see.
I should put them in the containers.
Oh, dear.
Oh, my. You both did a great job.
I want to give her a massage after this...
because she worked so hard.
I feel so sorry.
She's so nice.
She has a warm heart.
I know. That's why I don't call her...
I don't call her my mother-in-law.
- You call her your mom. - She's my mom.
She's really... You know, that's...
While making kimchi, I think she became serious.
She thought it'd be simple and easy...
to make the filling and put it between leaves.
She had no idea...
- it would be this hard. - Of course.
- Is there anything else? - No.
- Are you sure? - No.
- It's done? - Oh, my gosh.
- Yes! - You both did a great job.
Great job, everyone.
Dear me.
Gosh, my back.
Oh, my legs! My everything!
Everything. My whole body is aching.
We made a lot of kimchi.
Kany, let's eat bossam so that you can go home.
- Really? - Yes.
Yes! Great.
(Really? Yes!)
- Oh, my. - Look at that.
But that was fun.
(They finally finished making kimchi with 70 heads of napa cabbage.)
I'm going to eat a lot.
(With young radish kimchi, there's a lot of kimchi here.)
- How did you do all that? - You used all 70 heads.
In one day.
(KEY is exhausted...)
(from making kimchi with 70 heads of napa cabbage in 1 day.)
(Both KEY and Kany are exhausted.)
Kany, here's oyster bossam for you.
Hold on. I'll make the sauce quickly.
Kany's mother-in-law has the highest stamina among the three.
- Exactly. - That's right.
She doesn't even seem tired.
Oh, my gosh.
- My, homemade food. - It looks good.
(Well-cooked suyuk)
(And today's star, kimchi)
(Fresh raw oyster)
(Chewy half-dried saury)
You can't go wrong with half-dried saury.
She also made acorn jelly.
(Acorn jelly that she made with her own hands)
(And her own secret sauce)
- Nothing here is from a store. - That's right.
How is that possible?
- Making them alone must be tiring. - She's really incredible.
Try it with some oysters. And try the half-dried saury too.
- Didn't I bring... Oh, it's here. - Here.
(The touching moment of having his first bite)
Is it good?
(Amazed)
Really?
(She makes a vegetable wrap carefully with an oyster.)
Did you put it in there?
- They're enjoying winter food. - This is killing me.
I wonder if it's tasty.
- I'll cut it for you with my hands. - Okay.
Thank you.
You're supposed to tear kimchi like this. This is the right way.
- It tastes so good. - Korean food is popular globally.
And you can't enjoy that taste anywhere else in the world.
- You're right. - You can't find that.
- You can enjoy it only in Korea. - That's right.
- You... - Mom, please eat.
(Shall I?)
- Why? - Too much.
(She finally has a bite.)
- Thank you. - Have that piece.
Gosh, this is...
(He picks up a strip of freshly made kimchi.)
That looks crazy good.
Oh, my.
(He puts everything in his mouth.)
(The joy that came after long, hard work)
(The fantastic combination)
(Mother's acorn jelly and her secret sauce)
That sauce was crazy good.
She must've made it deliciously.
Oh, my.
I visit my friends on my days off...
and help them make kimchi, which I haven't done before.
Or I invite a friend over and cook for him or her.
That's my own way of showing my love for them.
It's to let them know that I care about them.
It's to express how much I adore them.
Rather than just saying it to them,
I want to show my affection through my actions...
and hear what they think.
I believe it's a good way of communicating with others.
All right. Now...
Kany, you should go home and rest too. You worked hard.
- You worked really hard. - You too.
I'll stay a little longer and eat some more.
- Take your time and eat a lot. - Right. Eat a lot.
(Kimchi Conveys Love)
(Next story)
(Someone is cleaning his room like crazy.)
(Is he Kang Yong?)
(What time is it?)
(He crams his clothes in his closet hastily.)
(He's covering the mess.)
(I can finish this in 1 minute.)
(A very important person for me...)
(is visiting my house after a long time.)
(So I cleaned the house hastily and prepared to welcome her.)
(The important person for him is...)
(Kang Yong's mother!)
(The mother and son, who look alike, meet each other.)
(My house is clean and tidy, right?)
(Smiling)
(You should vacuum here again.)
(Can you give it a quick wipe?)
(He did his best to clean the house, but his mother cleans it again.)
(He keeps saying, "I'll do it.")
(He tries to distract her.)
(How about you have a walnut cake instead of cleaning?)
(I won an award too.)
(They make good memories.)
(And he successfully distracts her.)
(He kills 2 birds with 1 stone.)
(She brought a gift for her loving son.)
(A lucky broom with sensitive girl vibes)
(Shall I hang it here?)
(I'll hang it myself, my son.)
(Son! Can you give me a cup of tea?)
(Tea?)
(Chuckling)
(I brought floral coasters too.)
(His house is becoming pretty?)
(Wait. This isn't right.)
(The mother and son, who look alike, have warm hearts.)
(Salute!)
(MINHO salutes someone?)
(At ease)
(They're MINHO's fellow marines.)
(Salute!)
(I am Choi Min Ho, the 1,245th batch.)
(With those who were his senior and junior in the military...)
(To end 2025 well,)
(we went to Gangwon Province.)
(Is it 11km? That's a piece of cake.)
(They're going to climb up a mountain in winter.)
(They prepare themselves thoroughly, tightening their combat boots.)
(Once a marine, always a marine.)
(Won't your ears be cold?)
(I can overcome it with my passion.)
(If they're cold, I'll cut off one of them.)
(Wait for us, winter mountain.)
(Ghost-catching marines)
(Shouting)
(We'll run right up to the top of the mountain!)
(Slurping)
(Because we have to eat cup ramyeon.)
(It's basically a ramyeon eating challenge.)
(We climbed up here for this.)
(Ramyeon tastes so good on top of the mountain.)
I feel like I'm back in time.
(This why we climb up a mountain in winter.)
(The taste they will enjoy next is...)
(a sleigh ride!)
(It's exciting.)
(We have to make a bet.)
(Their pride as former marines is on the line.)
(Are you ready?)
(Screaming)
(Let's go.)
(This Is the Taste of Winter)